[Applause]
Welcome to the Business Central launch
event 2025 release wave 1. We are
thrilled that so many partners and
customers are joining us online today.
uh over 4,000 actually. Thank you for
taking the time and being with
us. We have an enormous uh amount of
content to show you. Uh you might have
been um wondering about the cheering in
the room. Uh today we're broadcasting
from Microsoft Development Center in
Denmark. And with us in the room are
many of the Business Central speakers
and our colleagues. You might also see
Thank you.
You might also see that some of our
colleagues will have their computers
open and that is because you online have
an option to ask questions in the Q&A
tab. Please do so. We are here in the
room ready to answer your questions.
Hot of the press, it's less than an hour
ago that we actually shipped Business
Central 2025 release wave 1. And here we
are ready to show you
more. Maya, you have been in the studio
with many of the speakers that we have
in the room today. Yes. Tell us a little
bit what's new this time. Yeah, so in
the last release, we changed the format
to be even shorter and easier to
navigate by adding chapters. We have
gotten so much positive feedback this
time around and more views on our video.
So, we actually decided to keep it, but
we still wanted to make it even better.
So, this time around, we have actually
split some of the sessions that would
have previously been one longer one into
different features to make it easier for
you guys also later on to find it again.
So, for instance, for sustainability, we
have value chain automation which we've
now divided into transfer process and
assembly automation orders. maybe. No,
I'm kidding. Um, yes, but we won't not
miss any information. We want you to
have the full overview. So, we've added
links to all the different videos
underneath each one to make it easy for
you guys to find everything. Um, so this
time around, we actually have 60 plus
videos byite-sized for you guys at home.
And we have an amount of 10 hours that
you guys can use to learn what's new in
Business Central. Um, they're designed
to help you with your pitches, stay
updated, but also be at your best and
talk to customers. And talk to
customers. Um, so yeah, they'll be live
after this live opening. So, we hope you
go and watch them all.
Thank you. We hope you're excited. And
you can find them all on YouTube. You
see them all here listed on uh on this
slide. But what's more once you've
watched the sessions um do join us uh in
a few weeks uh end of April we will have
a number of online office hours where
you can come and ask your questions to
all our subject matter experts and
speakers. Uh you can also actually
submit your questions in beforehand or
you can just come and ask your questions
uh in the sessions. Um then you might
wonder where do I uh get all of that
information? Um there is uh a couple of
ways. Uh watch out for the email that
you will receive after this session. Uh
there will be more information, but you
can always go to our LinkedIn page and
find more information about uh the
latest news uh for Business Central and
we will also have information on these
Q&A
sessions. Now, we don't want to keep you
any longer. Uh let's have uh Dimmitri
and Yanik on the stage um to tell about
the highlights.
Hello everybody. I am Yanik Ba and my
name is Ditri Shadv and it's so great to
see all you partners out there sitting
and watching this and spending actually
an hour with us. But of course also our
dear colleagues that actually is the
reason we are standing here because you
have been building great products yet
again. So thank you for that. Thank you
for that. And we did ship it, didn't we,
just now? Christina, what's the latest?
Oh, thank God. Thank God. No, no, please
don't joke with that. We did ship it.
Thank you so much. Yeah. Welcome.
Welcome. So, maybe I should start with
one of the big announcements uh for this
release. It's uh very simple. It's uh
actually a URL because finally we got
it. We got business central.com. So
every time you want to go back to uh the
the page where you can read about
business central you can just write
business central.com and it will of
course be autodirected to whatever
region country you are in. So also for
you partners watching out there um it's
a great way to put into material and
other things uh when you want to just
point customers to one place or for you
customers to go and find the latest
information about business. Look at it
right there. The signature business
central simplicity. Nothing else to
remember. Business
central.com. How amazing is that?
Correct. So, Dimmitri, yeah, I wanted to
start with this number. So, the number
is very special to this release 200. So,
what might it be? You might be asking
yourselves. And a little less than a
month ago, we shipped a brand new
product
capability revolutionizing the way the
sales process is done in the companies.
And I bet many of you already know that
we talk about the sales order agent. And
that was the number of agents spun up by
you trying it out in the very early
early stages of preview in actual
environments online. 200 agents spun up
and working for you right there. So this
is an incredible start, but there's just
so much more to uh to go through. So, we
want to show you all of the other
capabilities, including the capabilities
which the agent can do for you. And by
the way, there's surprise coming. It's
not the only agent in the business
central portfolio. But we also wanted to
cover most of our investments, fantastic
investments into so many areas of this.
Yeah. And we see there you know we've
done the AI powered business investments
basically going through all the
functionality areas of business central
and once again investing in those
including a lot of investments on the
reporting part and of course also genai.
Yes. And we have never forgotten. We we
did not forgot and we have never
forgotten and we will never forget about
our partners and our developers and
people who need to be productive need to
bring more and more customers on board
uh show them the the the the beauty of
Business Central and be be very
efficient. So all of our investments in
development administration keeping the
service resilient up like always up
always available. This is something that
you will see in just a few moments
hopefully. And Demetri, I'll let you uh
talk to the next part because we're
going to hear about the the sales order
agent. Yes. Yes. Sales order agent.
Thank you, Yanni.
Yes. So, you may have seen splashes on
social media and some of the
testimonials that our first customers
have given us about the sales order
agent. Sales agent can help businesses
drive b drive the process of sales. So
it can read literally emails understand
what's being asked that when the
customers are asking for a sales quote
it can understand which items are being
asked for. It can create the quote in
business central pro uh product. It can
create multiple lines. It can match it
with the right pricing and right SKs and
right information and it can generate
beautiful emails. all of that while
staying within the confines of its um
permissions and working securely and
helping your your sales team like being
a being a solid sales team member. So
all of this is now available for you to
try in the priv in the public preview
and we have expanded this p public
preview into many many more countries.
This is so exciting to announce that the
sales order agent is going to many more
countries around the world. So it's gone
into Canada, United States, Australia,
Great Britain, New Zealand. There's a
lot of wise space to cover. So we will
get there, but we want to start with
with these countries. Welcome on board.
Try it out. Give us the feedback. This
is an amazing new capability that you
don't want to miss. I wanted to also
mention that all the way through the
private preview we've been talking to
many customers and many partners and
many of uh of of people in this team in
this very room were working hard to
implement the feedback from these
discussions. So we're not just talking
we're actually applying the learnings to
this to the product and this was the
very first capability which we added
based on the public private preview
engagement. We know that every single
business cares deeply about the topic of
item availability. How to work with item
availability. So we made it simple for
the agent to understand and work with
item availability just like we also at
the same time with the same capability
made it simple for the end users for all
of you customers out there to work with
this topic. So now there is a dedicated
part of the experience where you can try
and assess the availability of your
items based on location based on the
requested delivery date quantity all of
these things. It is made available for
the end users it is also made available
for the sales order agent. So this is a
fantastic
combination. Another big capability
which we added there based on the
request from from many of you in the
private preview we are incorporating
more insights uh into the emails which
generated by the agent. So many of you
asked about hey we want in these emails
to see availability discounts uh pricing
information now it's all there it's all
available in a nice templates generated
fully with the power of AI and many many
more new capabilities stemming from the
private preview from the actual
conversations with the customers out
there uh generating customers on the
flight if the agent cannot find the
customer it will create it uh using your
your email uh box just to try and test
the agent and things of that nature.
Ability to review the the PDF. By the
way, spoiler alert, you can preview PDFs
now and agent benefits from that and
obviously the rest of the customers do
the same. And one other thing which I
wanted to to announce as well is that
this is something new which is entering
into the world of business central is a
is a agent billing capability while in
private preview. So we are going to
introduce uh and we have actually
already introduced the way to to build
for the agent consumption. It's a very
very simple model. It's been used by
power platform for a few years now. The
a the agent is going to be uh monetized
in a consumption unit which is called
message. So generally every time when a
certain event happens when the agent is
doing the operation creates an email or
creates a quote we'll charge you a
certain number of messages and it's very
easy to get these messages as a prepaid
capacity pack or you can configure pay
as you go and consume these messages as
you keep exploring the capabilities of
the sales order agent. So there's a lot
more to learn in this topic. It's a very
simple model. Hopefully, it's going to
it's going to pick up and be very very
clear, transparent for for all of you.
But like I mentioned, this was just the
beginning of Business Central agentic
story. So, we're moving beyond the first
agent already now. So, other areas of
business central cannot wait to be
optimized in exactly the same way.
Yanik, what do we have in stock? That is
so true. Thank you, Dmitri, for taking
us through the sales order agent. So,
What we are announcing now is the
payables agent. That is the next step uh
in terms of the investments we are doing
on the agentic framework. And um
actually I'm going to take you through a
short demo of that. That's probably the
easiest way to explain what is it doing.
So if we start here on the roll center,
we can see Stan coming to the office.
Somebody has switched on already the
payables agent. He gets a small
notification up here saying there's
something to review. He has received a
invoice for merchandise. And of course
it's going to look at that. And um he's
now opening. Okay, there is an invoice.
It's a PDF coming in. Let me go and
press review here. And as we now uh see
here, it's basically that PDF we see on
the right hand side being uh read with
Ashure intelligence. And this is
actually the invoice and all the
information that was captured. Why am I
showing this in full screen? Basically
just to understand the complexity that
now goes into having that recorded into
the system. There is some logo design.
There's some t-shirt in different sizes.
There is even some prepaid managed
storage for 12 months that is also
prepaid. So that uh has to be recorded
of course in a special way in business
central. But now the payables agent has
taken that information and used AI to
first of all put the design on an
allocation account allocating between
design and marketing. It has taken all
the items and actually split it out by
the variance. uh there it has also used
the knowledge of something that is
prepaid um and also the freights here
you can see that last line putting that
uh the shipping there and the prepaid
one it has used the deferral code in
this case 12 months so using a lot of
the knowledge that you would normally
have in the head of a bookkeeper
accountant that's being put in here into
the system using the AI once the person
here is done Stan is done on on this he
can then go to um end of the day or the
person that have set these agents up can
go and have a look at how much has
actually been processed, what is the
result, what is the efficiency and see a
lot of hours has been saved by using
this payables agent. So that's uh coming
in business central right now. If we
talk about coming uh in business central
it's in private preview some of the
components first of all the e document
uh connector uh which now supports uh
both the PDF but also sharepoint one
drive and of course the different
connectors uh to different e document
services. There's also a new page
collecting all that. And finally, there
is also the new purchase document draft
where we take whatever we read and
showcase that in a full uh readable um
overview in Business Central. What's
coming next? Later this year, you're
going to see a public preview of that
agent being able to process these
invoices, but of course also support
reading from the PDF and most
importantly having that intelligent
accounting knowledge that it uses to put
things in the right account, put it in
the right um inventory uh or in the
right deal accounts. That's coming um
end of this year. Now talking about
investments in AI, uh these were the
agents, but of course we continued the
journey on uh Copilot as well. And this
one is, you know, one of the really cool
ones here. Um that's autofill um fields
with Copilot. Uh let me actually show
that in full screen for you so you can
see what's going on here. Here I have a
customer card and I now have to uh
create a new um customer. In this case
it is I have to press here it is
adventure works. I'll put that in and I
will click that little icon. You saw
that there which is the autofill icon.
It um it takes that as a suggestion
here. You can see when I do that it
fills out a field based on frequent
choice. It fills out this field
basically due to recently used values
and the next one because that customer
apparently is in the US it selects North
America for the address. I also press
the icon here and then it fills out by
using a web search. In this case it's
using Bing search and I can finally go
and accept it all. That's autofill.
That's autofill on any cart page that
really enables faster entry of any data
into Business Central.
Yeah. Then summarize with co-pilot
another investment done in uh this
release. And again, let me show you what
that's about. We have a customer card
here again. And uh as I go to this
summary, it first starts when I
basically wanted to expand and then it
works on finding interesting information
about that customer card I've opened or
whatever card I've opened. In this case,
I can also drill down and see some of
the invoices it has called out and
notice also some of the comments that
Copilot adds. It really gives me the
possibility to learn more about the
customer and in this case also show more
information. So when you have to call
somebody, you can use this and get a lot
of rich information preparing for for
any caller. It could be a vendor, it
could be items, whatever. That's the
summarize feature. We done more with
co-pilot but before I show you that I
want to say that we built it on the
sustainability investment. So let's just
cover those first. Um the whole
sustainability module in business
central has been expanded further. Uh
for example it now uh takes care of
water and waste in this release but also
the most important uh scope 3 emissions
which are the emissions from your
suppliers and so on. It actually can be
now be automated and captured in
business central as well. But there's
one thing there is one thing about this
sustainability tracking and that is for
anybody to actually understand what
emission factors to use because if
you're driving a small car there's a big
difference from buy driving a large car.
So we have of course solved that with
co-pilot. So you can now suggest
emissions with co-pilot in this release.
I'm not going to show you a video here.
You will be able to see that in the BCLE
videos, a full story on that. But if you
could just read the the fine print here,
it says company car. It says something
about a hotel or even a flight in in
this little screenshot. And we're using
that information for example on the
flight what was the route and using that
we can calculate uh the emissions to be
used when you have to report your your
your carbon footprint. So uh really
really a timesaver for sustainability
reporting. going
forward. E documents, uh you saw a
little bit of that in the payables.
We're using some compo components of
that, but we continue to invest. There's
60 countries around the world right now
that mandates um electronic document
exchange. 20 more coming uh soon as as
well. So this is an investment we're
doing both for supporting uh the agentic
experience with payables agents and
other agents but also due to the fact
that we simply have to do this from a
regulatory point of view. For example,
one of the investments here is send it
by email. Yes, there are some countries
where you haven't set up you know
requirements for sending it over some
servers whatever. So you need to do it
via email. So of course we built that in
this release. And as I've been doing
this, you can also see that we've added
uh additional capabilities with C-Pilot
being able to match orders better.
Actually also record things like item
references when you are using this
system. It will record that so that
Copilot doesn't have to be used for
matching later. That is something that
is then just looked up when the same
items appear uh on a on a purchase
document to be matched.
now ah lot more so I'll continue here
manufacturing what you probably noticed
uh for the last couple of releases we
have taken a focus on we started
inventory then we did service then we
did project then we opened the hood so
to say on manufacturing in this release
have done a lot of uh improvements there
and while you know you read this here I
really encourage you those of you doing
something with manufacturing go see the
BCL videos on this because there are
some really really great time savers uh
there and if you're a customer watching
using manufacturing you will for example
love that you can now block the output
of uh production orders so that you
don't produce items that you basically
stop selling that was not possible
before it's possible now or there are
the two of those on this slide you see
here um the cancel production order or
the reopen
That's something that takes hours and
minutes in some cases because a lot of
products have been used and it all has
to be put back on stock at the right
value and everything. So this is going
to be a huge time savers for people. I
wouldn't say you know the mix you know
or change the mind at some point but
that's really that's what happens in a
business. You want to change due to
demand or other things you can go in
with a click of button and make that
change in this release. So go uh look at
that recording if you're doing anything
with manufacturing. Now what you will
see for all the application areas in
business central uh and you also saw
that in the overview slide that we've
done a lot of improvements for both the
PowerBI reports with and then also Excel
uh reports including Excel layouts and
as you can see here for example there is
a screenshot of the route planning in
manufacturing one of the reports uh
there. So again if uh you either a
customer using this system and haven't
seen this you can actually now go enable
all these rich reports for whatever uh
area you are using and if you're a
partner you would of course not go
around to any uh prospective customers
without showing the rich report sets we
now have. I'll come back a little bit to
this as well later. Shopify Shopify is
still you know having a huge growth both
uh in terms of e-commerce but also in
terms of the connector to business uh
central a lot of companies are going uh
online selling their products online or
whether it's to customers or B2B uh
which is also possible with with Shopify
which then demands us to respond to some
of the feedback we are getting. One of
the things we released uh recently uh as
you can see here, one of them is um the
capability for example to select your
sales channels. Uh you want to make sure
that this product maybe goes online for
sales but other products go for the
point of sale um because you can
actually run both point of sales and
online in a Shopify world or other sales
channels. That's now possible. There are
other things we've improved here and
that's things like u the um what is it
called? It's called the meta fields. We
in the last release we uh introduced it
for products. We've now introducing it
for customers. What is that? It's
basically Shopify's way of enabling
users to define their own fields. That's
called meter fields. We have now the
possibility for the customers as well to
bring them into business central and see
what rich information has been added for
those fields over over there. And then a
lot of other uh great improvements.
subscription billing. We did that in the
last release and when we introduce
something new, we often get some
feedback even though of course we do a
lot of due diligence, a lot of research
for every new feature we uh announce out
there. But subscription billing um was
just released. So we got some feedback,
a little bit of the terminology. We
don't call it service anymore. A little
bit of confusion there. It's now
subscription all over. Uh and a lot of
improvements in terms of the UI and
other things. H you actually the way you
get onboarded to this uh um capability
as well and as you can see here in the
screenshot of course rich PowerBI
reports have been added as well um for
example in a subscription business it's
very important as you can see here is
with small but uh to have churn analysis
you want to know who is churning how
many how many are churning what can I do
to bring them back so that's in uh this
release as well I already talked a
little bit about this So let's just uh
you know conclude here by again reports
it's in all areas whether it's PowerBI
excels and so on. This is a nice uh uh
screenshot of one of the financial
reports where you now have the
possibility to easily filter change the
layouts as well and later save them and
and and use them in a new way. So that's
uh available throughout the system.
Talking about analysis, um, as you know,
we introduced analysis mode several
releases ago and then lately we did, you
know, added the capability to build your
analysis views with co-pilot describing
what you want to see. One of the things
that we're missing which is now as you
can see soon coming. It's coming in one
of the minor releases is the capability
of actually adding fields from related
pages or everything that is related via
a table. Um those fields will then show
up and you can pick those as well to
build your rich analysis
view. Business central and field service
integration. Yes, I will keep talking
but uh there is a
lot. I mean you guys have been so busy
so if it's boring is you you you did it
man there's so much here anyway uh field
service integration uh last release we
had the integration with projects we
were missing the service order to work
order in field service it is there now
including a ton of other improvements in
this module it's very important of
course to have a great integration to
field service because field service uh
frontline workers um as it says material
there is about two billion of those and
it's one of those areas that is late in
digitalization. So by having a great
integration to field service we are
basically able to tap into that great
market opportunity helping people that
do frontline work with a much better
experience because again we will then
back office wise be able to quickly
invoice help these companies get paid
faster and so on by having built this
integration. Uh so go look at that video
as as well uh on BCLE if you're working
with
this. Last but not least or almost last,
let me say that. Um there's of course a
lot of improvements to the user
experience and we decided uh that again
here points to go see that full uh video
in BCLE but you saw some of it already.
You saw the uh PDF viewing of uh
attachments. No more download open again
to see it's just there in the client.
One of those I love is the resizing of
fact boxes. Yes, you can do that now.
It's possible.
Yes. And as it says here, optimized
screen estate usage. I mean maybe, you
know, thinking, okay, what's that? It's
actually now possible to see most of the
labels for fields which were previously
cut off. Uh that's been optimized. You
can actually read those fields and the
user can with a glance quickly
understand what's going on on a cart
page here. Love it. Love it. Love it. So
go watch that video and see all those
improvements. And if you're a user, you
definitely need to to go see it. And if
you're a customer there, yes, that's
that's where you will learn a lot. I
want to say thank you. Um actually also
with this slide, I want to say thank you
to all uh you out there um watching this
that has helped with contributions.
Contribution is uh contributions to the
business central product in ter in terms
of code. We of course internally have
several review processes of it but we
get u feedback from developers out there
say you should maybe change this or
that. I've done it for you and that's
happened 159 times in this release. So
thank you very much for doing
that. Two final things for me um before
Dimmitri pulls me down on the stage
here. Um, I want to just call this out
as well. AKMSBC capabilities or you
could go to business central.com and
then say download capability guide. It's
basically expanded by 100% uh with this
release meaning that we are now
describing every feature area of
Business Central. As you can read on the
slide, a lot of areas were actually not
even mentioned in this guide. So they're
there now and both for you as a customer
maybe getting inspired to use other
areas of Business Central or for you
partners out there that basically just
want to learn about a certain area.
Maybe you're new to this or for the
internal team that thinking what are we
actually doing in that area? Let me go
read it. So everybody this is you know
just one source of the truth of Business
Central. Go read that on your holiday or
whatever you know. Um this is more for
partners out there. So just want to
cover that quickly. There are new pit
stacks lately. Uh the power platform and
the subscription pit stacks. That's
basically where we talk about the value
to you customers out there explaining
what we've done in business central not
only the latest but just in any release
and talk about the value of uh these
areas. More to come in this. That's last
word for me. So I'll welcome Dimmitri
back on stage.
Unbelievable. Thank you. Thank you,
Yanni. It is unbelievable. You know, I
was watching here from the corner of of
the room and it feels like you guys have
built a brand new product to be honest.
So, how can this even happen every
release? Supply chain,
manufacturing, beautiful UX, AI,
reporting, analytics, just so many
things. It's hard to fit it all. No
wonder Yanik is out of breath, you know,
just listing these things. It's it's
incredible. Thank you so much. Fantastic
work everyone. And um I wanted to start
it is in another interesting area. Um
this is the topic that we've been
talking about for quite some time. Uh
the area is called flexible update
management and many of you may already
know what this is about. Uh not every
customer is the same. So there are
situations where you need to accommodate
for customer needs. In this context I
wanted to say that actually vast
majority of our customers are migrating
at the same time and the same cadence as
we ship our releases. So even though we
ship so so much capabilities so much
features customers majority of our
customers stay along stay upgraded and
move forward with the releases and get
benefits of all of these improvements.
But like I said, not every customer is
the same. So sometimes you need to
accommodate for customer requirements.
Sometimes you as a partner need to
prepare for the release better. You need
to uh learn all of these fantastic
capabilities yourself. You need to
schedule your time with your key partner
and customer and then go and implement
and update this solution which by the
way happens just by scheduling the
update and it happens overnight. But
there's a lot of preparation and
learning that that that needs to happen
before that is a success. So we made it
possible for you uh for those cases
where customers needed to reschedule
update. And in this beautiful animation
made by yours truly, you can see how you
as a partner can create uh you can you
can schedule environments to any
available version of business central u
that is a minor update and next major
update but also to the updates which are
planned beyond the major version. So you
have a range of multiple versions that
you can select to go to specifically uh
depending on your readiness, depending
on the customer readiness or your needs.
So very very flexible uh system. You can
also by the way create new environments
based on any of these versions which are
available in that dropdown which is
super important for all of your cloud
migration projects, for all of your
testing projects and other activities.
By the way, you may spotted a red no uh
word on this list and I wanted to draw
your attention to this because with all
of this flexibility, there will be no
opportunity and possibility and tooling.
We wiped away that piece of
functionality in our service. I'm almost
kidding, but I'm being serious. To
postpone updates beyond that point in
time. So please use that extended window
to get ready to upgrade because there
will be no option to postpone updates
beyond that grace
period. Another thing which I wanted to
mention is something that we were we
wanted to do for for some time. We
wanted to bring all of the extensions
into exactly the same surface in the
business central admin center. So now on
this beautiful screenshot and I keep
telling that these are the beautiful
screenshots built by this amazing team
right here in the room and not just the
screenshot the product behind the
screenshots as well. So on this
screenshot you see three worlds joining
together the global extensions the per
tenant extensions and dev extensions in
the same view. So now you as an
administrator of this environment can
spot all of your extensions installed
and you can manage them with exactly the
same administration API in exactly the
same way. So you can list your
extensions, you can uninstall your per
tenant extensions and dev extensions,
you can automate that with the admin
center API. Huge improvement.
Another magnificent feature which has
been awaited by the partner channel for
a very very long time is your ability to
scale across multiple customers. You
know that in many many cases and we know
that many of you have to manage multiple
customers. So multiple um environments
to maintain. So how can you automate
that process? How do you schedule
updates in bulk? How do you, you know,
for example, uh, add change the list of
recipients in bulk across all of your
environments? With this release, we're
bringing a new endpoint, the one to rule
them all. It's called tenant discovery
endpoint. So with this endpoint, you as
a partner can find all of the tenants
and all of the environments which
granted access to your
application to work with that
environment. So very very simple API you
can query which which environments
allowed you to uh administrate them and
allow allow you to call this admin
operations and you can iterate through
this environments and do the admin
operations across tenants super easy you
can build a lot of automation on top of
it so very very flexible I can't wait to
see how this API is is taken by by you
partners one other thing which I wanted
to is uh you know that we are extremely
privacy conscious organization privacy
and security and all data in business
central is encrypted at multiple layers
in our architecture. So it is encrypted
everywhere. If I start listing the list
of places where we encrypt your customer
data, this will be going on until the
rest of the presentation. But we added
yet another layer of encryption. Uh for
those of you uh which need this
additional layer for example for some of
the government organization for some of
the organizations where there is a a an
an regional requirements or or
government requirements to have data
encrypted additionally with the key
which is owned by your organization. Now
this is an option. So you can bring your
own managed um managed encryption key.
we will take that key and use it to
encrypt your data and just on top of all
other encryption which we're doing in
our service. So this is another option
for you to assess.
What we see happening across the world
uh with the customer implementation is
that partners spending a lot of time
building
reports to our you know in our studies
up to 25% of implementation time can be
spent on just tweaking and modifying the
reports and report layout. So, every
customer wants to have their report
built in their own way. And for that, we
introduced an add-on which allows you to
build and customize reports using
Microsoft Word, which is an amazing tool
for doing just that. It's super
flexible. It's open. Uh, everyone knows
it. And we added with this adon several
capabilities to uh, for example, manage
the visibility of controls uh, on these
report layouts. uh change the layout
completely, changing fonts, doing the
simple operations very very easily. And
with this report, with this release, we
adding another capability for you to
pick the most frequently used properties
which you would previously need to code
into the object into the actual report
object. Now you can just pick these
properties such as was the company name,
when was the report last run, who was
the user, uh you know, you can pick it
from the conveniently presented u date
picker. So right here, a field picker
and put them onto your report and have
them running for your customers. So a
lot of simplification done right there.
Another area which is which has
undergone quite a lot of uh interesting
changes is an area which I'm sure near
and dear to many of your hearts. So it's
an accurate inventory
evaluation. Thank
you. My heart warms up as I just say
this word accurate inventory evaluation.
This is a really really I'm I'm not even
I'm I'm being serious now. This is a
really critical process for so many
organizations out there. If you're doing
cost adjustments for all of your
inventory for so many, you know,
transactions happening day in day out,
you need to have a reliable tool uh to
do it in a in a proper way to begin with
and then to to make sure that you can
you can iterate on this and um and
ensure the accurate uh entries and
transactions are posted into the system.
So with this release, additional
capabilities were included with Business
Central which allows you for example to
do iterative adjustments. So you can
adjust your inventory period by period
or even item by item. So the granularity
is spectacular with this tool. You can
do forced adjustments for the runs which
you considered uh being done
incorrectly. So you want to revisit
these entries and force readjust these
calculations. And we also helping you
with a lot of insights uh for self
diagnostics. The tool will run through
your setup. We'll run through the
transactions and give you hints and
practical guidance what needs to be
changed in order for the cost adjustment
to run smoothly. This is a massive help
to you partners doing support and help
of your customers. It is also a
massively impactful tool for the
customers out there doing the doing
these cost adjustment improvements uh
every every day or every week. So thanks
a lot team. This is an amazing
improvements to the product.
So now we're moving into another domain
of BC uh developers. And I'm not going
to say it three times. I'm just going to
say it once
developers. But developers are super
critical to to the growth of our
product. And this release was not an
exception. We added so many different
features and capabilities to the
language to the development environment
and um to to the entire ecosystem of
developing code for business central.
You see some of the features here on the
list. One of them for example moving
fields and tables between extensions is
a huge help to all of you doing
refactoring of your apps. So I would
imagine that many of your apps uh need
to be modernized, need to be refactored.
As you grow in functionality, you want
to modularize them. You make to make
them more nimble, more accurate, fitting
your business purposes. Now you have
tools for that. This was available for
for one or two releases, I believe, for
Microsoft Teams. We've enjoyed this
capability so much that we decided to
give it to all of you partners out
there. So you're welcome.
this. We can't wait to see uh all of the
impact that this is going to have on on
the partner channel. Also, some of the
absolutely critical pieces for for
modern development are included in this
release. Ability for you to bring over
your resources together with apps,
package resources into the same apps
where the code is presented. Uh easier
easier tools for working with JSON
formats and YAML. So these are
practically industry standards uh in
today's world and many many other
interesting improvements. One thing
which I wanted to bring up here normally
when we talk mocking we prefer to blame
it like we don't like mocking please
don't mock uh in general but in this
context mocking is amazing. What you can
do in this release you can mock external
services uh in API calls. So you can
write your code which pretends to be
talking to an external web service and
receive all of the pre pre-prepared
responses to be poss to to make it
possible to test these scenarios and
build reliable solutions. This is an
amazing capability for all of you test
obsessed and we all should be test
obsessed. So now you can you can use it
in the product uh building all of the
integration solutions and building tests
for all of your integration solutions
which can understand many different
interaction patterns uh in the code.
Moving on, you may have noticed in
Yanik's presentation that we were
showing a lot of beautiful
PowerBI and one of the reasons this
PowerBI was beautiful is because it was
wrapped into a an amazing canvas of
Business
Central. So, you've seen a very slim uh
line around the PowerBI control. We
given the PowerBI control all of the
space it needs, but it also feels very
natural in Business Central. So there's
no other actions, there's no other
components around this control around
this adding control. So all of the
attention is focused and yet it is part
of the business central experience. So
this is an this is a new uh page type
which you can use not only for embedding
PowerBI, you can use it for uh for other
controlins that you may have. For
example, it could be super useful for
post terminals. Um, now there's there's
going to be no destruction uh for the
users and yet it will be embedded into
the beautiful user experience of
BC. We also try to always optimize the
productivity of developers and partners
working in the combination of the web
client, the development uh Visual Studio
Code and the GitHub repository and and
whatever source control system that you
may have. This release is not an
exception. So we added additional
capabilities for you to be productive
when working in this trio. So what you
can do is you can uh jump directly from
the list of apps into the source code of
these apps. So you can stamp the source
code into the definition of the app and
get right there into the source code
into your source code system. Very
convenient. You can generate launch
configurations if you need to spin up
the Visual Studios uh VS Code solution
and connect to this environment.
Sometimes it can be super tricky to set
up this config file. The tool will just
do it for you. It will help you in this
process. You can connect the debugger.
You can create uh you can click with a
click of a button get the list of all of
the dependencies of a specific app. Grab
that list put them into your app and now
you have the list of your dependencies
defined. So all of these actions that
you see on this screen will help you be
much more productive as a developer or
techie consultant working in these three
of of products. The web client, the
Visual Studio Code, and your source
control
system. Now let's talk a little bit
about performance. Performance is top of
mind for so many of us like here in the
room and so many of us out there uh
watching through this uh
camera. And you may remember that in the
last release uh some big news hit like
hey we actually refactored the way we
post into warehouse entry uh to allow
many more concurrent operations to be
happening in that in that space. We got
a lot of excitement in this space. Many
customers came back and said this is
amazing can you push this
forward and boy we've pushed it
forward. So this is the list of other
posting operations and posting tables
which were posting you know tables yes
which were refactored the process was
refactored to allow much more
concurrency. So you see some of the hit
records on this list item ledger entry
value entry and job ledger entry.
There's so many critical posting
transactional tables which are now
unlocked for much more concurrency. You
might be asking how much more
concurrency and this is a number. So if
you run one batch job worth 1,000 sales
invoices uh you can get around one
invoice posted per second. If you run
five botches botches of 1,000 invoices,
your throughput will increase to 4.7
invoices per
second. So running more things in
parallel will get you will allow you to
to achieve much more throughput. And in
the old world, the world before this
release, the posting of the second batch
would have to wait for the first batch
to continue. Now they kick in at the
same time and push much more data
through Business Central. Amazing
improvement. And the team asked me to
put all of the asterises around the
324% percentages. And I did, but I'm not
going to talk about it. This is an
amazing improvement. Yes, it differs
from data to data, from database to
database, but you do get a ton of more
throughput through this posting
refactoring. Thank you so
much. Yes.
In the area of performance, we we we we
investigate all of the life site
incidents with all of the tickets that
we get in the area of performance and we
try to improve the things which slow the
pro product down. These are some of the
examples. We made it possible to skip
calculation of invisible flow fields
because it makes a complete sense. If
the field is not visible on the page,
don't calculate it when you show the
page. Now it's in the product. So now
your pages are much more responsive and
and uh faster to open. We made the
process of copying company much faster.
We made uh improvements for for those of
you troubleshooting performance as well.
So now you see much more insights in our
database way statistics page and index
uh missing indexes page to understand
which index out of several suggested by
the system is good for you. Which one is
going to provide the better impact at
lower cost. So there's just so many
interesting improvements and not only in
the tooling and troubleshooting area
also in the back end of the service. So
the service in this particular release
and we've been doing it over a series of
releases investing into different layers
of this architecture to make it much
more performant. The NST startup is much
faster. We're scaling much more rapidly
and much more aggressively to address
this extreme peaks in demand. Our memory
management has improved. Generally, the
system is much leaner. It consumes less
memory for its internal processes,
leaving all of the memory to all of you
and all of your processes. And
generally, we see the much more
consistent performance uh in in in our
service running on version 25 which is
out there in
production. And I wanted to wrap it up
on a very very important point. If you
manage all of your apps and you do
manage many many apps in your system,
they need to be controlled. The apps
need to be managed and for that we do
have a product called algo for GitHub.
There was several huge improvements in
this area as well. They happen
continuously. So it's not release to
release to release on a continuous
basis. We release new capabilities with
algo for GitHub with the product as
well. But in this in this DevOps
ecosystem uh also and this release is
not an exception. So there are several
changes in security and build
performance. Uh for example, we are not
uh we are not re rebuilding and
republishing the apps which have not
been changed. So your develops pipelines
are much faster, much more efficient.
You don't have to wait for your build.
I'm sorry developers out there, but you
will actually have to work because
waiting for your build to come is not
going to be an option. But you can
achieve much more with uh with this new
pipelines. We've improved the area of
testability as well. So you can you can
use page scripting tests. You can import
and employ your p your your automated
tests. You can import tests into online
environment. There's just so many
critical capabilities for your source
control system. Please take a look at
this series of videos and understand
what's in the package. And also if
you're one of these uh very happy uh
viewers of our monthly office hours,
please continue joining this monthly
office hours which happen on Tuesday um
last Tuesday every months. So join uh if
you are like that much caffeinated dog
like you are most welcome right there in
the corner. So join, ask your questions,
be there and uptake DevOps as soon as
you
can. This was the highlevel overview of
the capabilities which 2025 release wave
1 brings to us. You can find all of the
highlights, beautiful descriptions,
screenshots on aka.msbc release plan. We
strongly encourage you to go and and and
read through this. Please also, of
course, use the beautiful opportunity to
uh review all of the videos describing
everything that we just said and more in
much more
detail. So, wasn't that an epic release,
Yanik? It was. It was so many things.
So, thank you to all in the room here
for making yet another another great
release.
But with all of these investments,
somehow I still feel that that something
is missing. That is true. I mean I know
that 50% of our investments go into
security. Yes. Then there is a quarter
of investments into all everything else.
But there's another quarter which feels
missing. Like I have this strange
feeling that something we haven't
covered. Some critical investment of our
product. Yes. What we haven't covered
now is of course what we spend our time
on. That was writing and producing the
business central song. So let's hit it
and just play it. Phones out. Thank you
very much. Thank you so much. Look at
those again.
In the world of business, there's a shin
star. From finance to sales, it does it
all. Business Central, answering the
call. With every challenge, it stands
tall, helping us rise. Never let us
fall. Work smarter, adapt faster,
perform better. Business Central,
bringing us together. Work smarter,
adapt faster, perform better. Business
central, we'll conquer
forever. Streamlining processes, making
it right from morning till the end of
the night. Inventory projects and
HR2. Business central. There's nothing
you can do with every challenge. It
stands tall, helping us rise, never let
us fall. Work smarter, adapt faster,
perform better. Business central,
bringing us together. Work smarter,
adapt faster, perform better. Business
central, we'll conquer
forever.
[Music]
Innovation
at work smarter, adapt faster, perform
better. Business central bringing us
together. Work smarter, adapt faster,
perform better. Business central, we'll
conquer forever.
[Applause]